Guide to the Harry Weinberger Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Original accession, 1915-1943
  - Stange, Hugh
    The papers consist of letters, legal papers, notes, clippings, and miscellaneous papers concerning Hugh Stange vs. Samuel J. Washansky, 1934-1936. Washansky wrote letters to various motion picture companies and producers charging that Stange's play False Dreams Farewell was a direct infringement of Washansky's play Fastest Thing Afloat. Stange brought suit charging that Washansky was blocking sale of the motion picture rights of his play. The plays were finally submitted to a committee of arbitration that decided that both were based on events in the public domain. Stange's play was then bought by Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer Pictures.
    - Correspondence
      - American Arbitration Association (3), 1934 (Box 47, Folder 12)
      - The American Dramatists (2), 1934 (Box 47, Folder 12)
      - Century Play Co., Inc. (10), 1934-1935 (Box 47, Folder 13)
      - Fireman's Fund Indemnity Co. (2), 1934 (Box 47, Folder 13)
      - Fleischer, Sidney R. (16), 1934 (Box 47, Folder 14)
      - Koenig, Bachner, and Koenig (6), 1934, 1936 (Box 47, Folder 15)
      - Martin Lubell, Inc. (2), 1934 (Box 47, Folder 15)
      - Metro Goldwyn Mayer Pictures, Legal Department (4), 1936, 1941 (Box 47, Folder 15)
      - RKO Pictures, Inc. (3), 1934 (Box 47, Folder 16)
      - Stange, Hugh (16), 1936 (Box 47, Folder 16)
      - U.S. Circuit Court of Appeals (3), 1934 (Box 47, Folder 17)
      - Woolsey, John M. (2), 1934 (Box 47, Folder 17)
    - Legal papers, 1934, undated (Box 47, Folder 18-20)
    - Newspaper and magazine clippings, 1932, 1934 (Box 47, Folder 21)
    - Notes (Box 47, Folder 22)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 47, Folder 23)
  - Steimer, Mollie
    See: Abrams, Jacob, box 2, folders 10-11
    See: Abrams, Jacob, box 3, folders 5-6
  - Sternberg, Louis
    See: Kramer, Louis box 35, folders 26-31, box 36, folders 1-8
  - Theatre Alliance Inc.
    The papers consist of letters and miscellaneous papers. Weinberger was legal advisor for the Theatre Alliance Inc., a cooperative group of actors, directors, stage hands, technicians, and administrators.
    - Correspondence
      - C-D, F, K-N, W (18), 1935 (Box 48, Folder 1)
      - Cerf, Bennett A. (1), 1935 (Box 48, Folder 2)
      - Rice, Elmer (12), 1935 (Box 48, Folder 2)
      - Theatre Alliance Inc. (9), 1935 (Box 48, Folder 2)
      - Woolsey, John M. (1), 1935 (Box 48, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - Thorpe, Herbert A.
    The papers consist of letters, legal papers, notes, and miscellaneous paper concerning Herbert A. Thorpe vs. The Board of Education of the City of New York and New Jersey vs. Herbert A. Thorpe.
    Thorpe, like Weinberger, did not believe in the propriety of compulsory vaccination. Weinberger defended Thorpe in two cases arising from this belief. In the first, Thorpe refused to allow his two children to be vaccinated, thereby preventing them from entering school. The Board of Education charged Thorpe with violating the compulsory education law and Thorpe sued the Board for $10,000 damages. Both cases were dismissed. In the second case, Thorpe was fined five dollars for distributing pamphlets in public streets. The charge was dismissed.
    - Correspondence
      - L, N, R, S (19), 1911-1912, 1916-1918 (Box 48, Folder 4)
      - Heilenday, Frank W. (16), 1915-1917 (Box 48, Folder 5)
      - Higgins, Charles M. (4), 1910-1912 (Box 48, Folder 5)
      - New York City, Department of Education (4), 1910-1912 (Box 48, Folder 6)
      - New York Evening Sun (3), 1911 (Box 48, Folder 7)
      - New York State, Department of Education (2), 1910, 1912 (Box 48, Folder 7)
      - New York State, Department of Health (2), Undated (Box 48, Folder 7)
      - Thorpe, Herbert A. (20), 1910-1913, 1915, 1917 (Box 48, Folder 8)
    - Legal papers
      - A) New York vs. Thorpe
        - 1910-1913 (Box 48, Folder 9-10)
        - Notes (Box 48, Folder 11)
        - Miscellaneous (Box 48, Folder 12)
      - B) New Jersey vs. Thorpe
        - 1917 (Box 48, Folder 13)
        - Notes, miscellaneous (Box 48, Folder 14)
  - Three Arts Little Theatre
    The papers consist of letters and legal papers. Weinberger acted as legal advisor during the organization of the Three Arts Little Theatre.
    - Correspondence: Hallett, Louis (5), 1925 (Box 48, Folder 15)
    - Legal papers, 1925 (Box 48, Folder 16)
  - Toller, Ernst
    The papers consist of letters and notes concerning Ernst Toller vs. Maurice Schwartz, 1936-1937. Weinberger was retained by Toller to represent him in a dispute with Maurice Schwartz of the Freiheit Publishing House over the rights to Toller's play Bloody Laughter.
    - Correspondence
      - The American Dramatists (3), 1936 (Box 48, Folder 17)
      - Brodsky, Joseph R. (2), 1937 (Box 48, Folder 18)
      - Clark, Barrett H.
        See: The American Dramatists, box 48, folder 17
      - Freiheit (5), 1936-1937 (Box 48, Folder 18)
      - Schwartz, Maurice (1), 1936 (Box 48, Folder 19)
      - Toller, Ernst (12), 1936-1937 (Box 48, Folder 19)
    - Notes (Box 48, Folder 20)
  - Troy, Lillian S.
    The papers consist of letters, legal papers, and notes concerning Harry Weinberger vs. Lillian Scott Troy, 1919-1921. Weinberger helped Troy gain admittance to the United States and acted for her in some business dealings concerning her motion picture theatre in England. Troy contested Weinberger's fee, and most of these papers concern his attempts to collect money he claimed was due him.
    - Correspondence
      - Dintenfass, Mark M. (2), 1919 (Box 48, Folder 21)
      - Fine, Laurence M. (4), 1919 (Box 48, Folder 21)
      - Fitzgerald, M. Eleanor (1), 1919 (Box 48, Folder 21)
      - Irish Progressive League (10), 1919-1921 (Box 48, Folder 22)
      - Jury, William (4), 1919 (Box 48, Folder 22)
      - Kelly, Gertrude B. (8), 1919 (Box 48, Folder 22)
      - Northam, W. Arthur (3), 1919 (Box 48, Folder 23)
      - O'Leary, Jeremiah A. (15), 1920-1922 (Box 48, Folder 23)
      - The Orpheum, Ltd. (6), 1919-1920 (Box 48, Folder 23)
      - Partelle, Dwight J. (1), 1919 (Box 48, Folder 24)
      - Provincial Cinemagraph Theatres, Ltd. (1), 1919 (Box 48, Folder 24)
      - Troy, Lillian S. (15), 1919-1920 (Box 48, Folder 24)
      - U.S. District Court (3), 1919-1920 (Box 48, Folder 24)
    - Legal papers, 1917, 1919 (Box 48, Folder 25)
  - Vaccination
    The papers consist of letters, clippings, pamphlets, and miscellaneous papers. Weinberger considered compulsory vaccination to be a violation of personal freedom. This section contains a speech Weinberger made on the subject of "Medical Freedom" and copies of clippings, pamphlets, and magazines collected by Weinberger on this subject.
    - Correspondence
      - The Associated Press (1), 1915 (Box 49, Folder 1)
      - Daniel, H.A. (6), Undated (Box 49, Folder 1)
      - Danzinger, Samuel (1), 1915 (Box 49, Folder 2)
      - Higgins, Charles M. (8), 1915 (Box 49, Folder 2)
      - Loyster, James A. (1), 1915 (Box 49, Folder 2)
      - National League for Medical Freedom (4), 1915 (Box 49, Folder 3)
      - Pearlman, Nathan D. (5), 1915 (Box 49, Folder 3)
    - Newspaper and magazine clippings regarding vaccination, 1913, 1915 (Box 49, Folder 4)
    - Pamphlets regarding vaccination, 1898, 1902, 1904, 1907-1917, undated (Box 49, Folder 5-9)
    - "The Vaccination Inquirer", 1911, 1915-1918 (Box 49, Folder 10-11)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 49, Folder 12)
  - Vasquez, Leonardo L.
    See: Rangel, Jesus M. box 43, folder 26
  - Vazzani, Stefano
    The papers consist of letters concerning New York vs. Stefano Vazzani ex. rel. Andrew Maggio, 1917. Maggio was wounded by Vazzani and retained Weinberger to represent him.
    - Maggio, Andrew (1), 1917 (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - Vazzani, Stefano (2), 1917 (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - Vik, George
    The papers consist of letters. Vik was held for deportation to Finland after his illegal entry into the United States. Weinberger was retained by the Finnish Socialist Party to try to arrange for Vik to be deported to Argentina. Vik was finally deported to Finland.
    - English Consulate, New York (1), 1920 (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - Seger, Emil (5), 1920 (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - U.S. Department of Labor, Immigration (11), 1920 (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - Vik, George (7), 1920 (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - Vorse, Mary M. H.
    The papers consist of letters and legal papers. Weinberger drew up a will for Mary Marvin Heaton Vorse.
    - Correspondence
      - The Corn Exchange Bank (1), 1921 (Box 50, Folder 4)
      - Harn, Josephine G. (1), 1921 (Box 50, Folder 4)
      - Vorn, Mary M. H. (1), Undated (Box 50, Folder 4)
    - Legal papers, 1921 (Box 50, Folder 5)
  - Voss, Carl
    The papers consist of letters. Voss, an organizer for the International Workers of the World (I. W. W.), was arrested on a charge of criminal anarchy and held for deportation to Germany. Weinberger, retained by the Workers' Defense Union, attempted to have the charge against Voss dropped. Voss was finally deported to Germany.
    - American Civil Liberties Union (1), 1920 (Box 50, Folder 6)
    - Fitzgerald, M. Eleanor
      See: League for the Amnesty of Political Prisoners, box 50, folder 6
    - Flynn, E. G.
      See: Workers' Defense Union, box 50, folder 7
    - League for the Amnesty of Political Prisoners (1), 1920 (Box 50, Folder 6)
    - U.S. Department of Justice (4), 1920 (Box 50, Folder 6)
    - U.S. Department of Labor, Immigration (11), 1920 (Box 50, Folder 7)
    - Voss, Carl (9), 1920 (Box 50, Folder 7)
    - Workers' Defense Union (4), 1920 (Box 50, Folder 7)
  - Walker, Joseph
  - Watson, Thomas E.
    The papers consist of letters. Senator Watson of Georgia retained Weinberger to negotiate for the re-publication of his books. Weinberger was unsuccessful.
    - Dodd, Mead, and Co. (4), 1918 (Box 50, Folder 8)
    - Doubleday, Page, and Co. (1), 1918 (Box 50, Folder 8)
    - Harper and Brothers (7), 1918 (Box 50, Folder 8)
    - Henry Holt and Co. (1), 1918 (Box 50, Folder 8)
    - Houghton, Mifflin Co. (1), 1918 (Box 50, Folder 9)
    - J.B. Lippincott Co. (1), 1918 (Box 50, Folder 9)
    - G.P. Putnam's Sons (1), 1918 (Box 50, Folder 9)
    - Watson, Thomas E. (13), 1918 (Box 50, Folder 9)
  - Weinberger, Erwin and Rita
    The papers consist of letters and legal papers concerning Erwin and Rita Weinberger vs. Trebuchs Realty Company. Weinberger represented the Weinbergers in a suit against the owners of the Ritz Theatre. Mrs. Weinberger charged that the theatre's negligence caused her to fall and injure herself. The case was settled out of court.
    - Correspondence
      - Attorneys Service Co. (1), 1927 (Box 50, Folder 10)
      - Steinhardt, I. D. (1), 1927 (Box 50, Folder 10)
      - Trebuchs Realty Co. (1), 1927 (Box 50, Folder 10)
      - Weinberger, Rita (1), 1926 (Box 50, Folder 10)
      - Woody, Robert H. (3), 1927, 1929 (Box 50, Folder 10)
    - Legal papers, 1927-1929 (Box 50, Folder 11)
  - Wu, Gray
    The papers consist of letters, legal papers, notes, and miscellaneous papers concerning New York vs. Gray Wu, 1919-1920. Wu, secretary of the Chinese United Association, a labor union, was arrested on a felonious assault charge along with Roy Chio, Woo Chow, and Lew Fat. The assault charge against all was dismissed due to lack of evidence. Wu was charged with having a gun and given an indeterminate sentence. Weinberger, attorney for the defendent, accused the Employers Association of a frame-up against Wu because of his labor activities.
    - Correspondence
      - C, D, F, K, M, N, R-T, W (18), 1919-1920 (Box 50, Folder 12)
      - Abbott, Leonard D. (1), 1919 (Box 50, Folder 13)
      - Chiu, Roy (6), 1919 (Box 50, Folder 13)
      - Chow, Woo (4), 1919 (Box 50, Folder 13)
      - Cohn, Michael A. (4), 1919 (Box 50, Folder 13)
      - DeSilver, Albert (1), 1919 (Box 50, Folder 14)
      - Fat, Lew (6), 1919 (Box 50, Folder 14)
      - General Defense Committee (5), 1919 (Box 50, Folder 14)
      - Kelly, Harry (9), 1919 (Box 50, Folder 15)
      - New York City District Attorney (6), 1919-1920 (Box 50, Folder 15)
      - New York City Parole Commission (3), 1919 (Box 50, Folder 15)
      - U.S. Department of Labor, Immigration (6), 1919 (Box 50, Folder 16)
      - Wu, Gray (25), 1919-1920 (Box 50, Folder 16)
    - Legal papers, 1919 (Box 50, Folder 17)
    - Notes, miscellaneous (Box 50, Folder 18)
  - Zogg, Nicholas S.
    The papers consist of letters, notes, and miscellaneous papers. Zogg was convicted for conspiracy to evade the Selective Service Act. Weinberger obtained a transfer for Zogg to the Atlanta Penitentiary because of his ill health. He obtained amnesty for Zogg in 1924.
    - Correspondence
      - C, H, N (5), 1919, 1922, 1924 (Box 50, Folder 19)
      - American Civil Liberties Union (8), 1923-1924 (Box 50, Folder 20)
      - Castleton, Samuel M. (4), 1919-1920 (Box 50, Folder 20)
      - Daugherty, Harry M.
        See: U.S. Department of Justice, box 50, folder 22
      - Joyce, Frank P. (1), 1920 (Box 50, Folder 21)
      - Kovner, Hilda (5), 1919 (Box 50, Folder 21)
      - U.S. Department of Justice (24), 1919-1921, 1924 (Box 50, Folder 22)
      - Zogg, Nicholas S. (15), 1919, 1921, 1924 (Box 50, Folder 22)
    - Notes, miscellaneous (Box 50, Folder 23)
  - Zumpano, Salvatore
    The papers consist of letters. Zumpano was being held for deportation to France. Weinberger obtained a sixty day postponement.
    - Correspondence
      - Andreyeff, Wasily (2), 1919 (Box 50, Folder 24)
      - DeSilver, Albert (2), 1919 (Box 50, Folder 24)
      - Flynn, Elizabeth G. (1), 1919 (Box 50, Folder 24)
      - Francioni, Alberto (8), 1919 (Box 50, Folder 25)
      - U.S. Department of Labor, Immigration (29), 1919 (Box 50, Folder 25)
      - Zumpano, Salvatore (19), 1919 (Box 50, Folder 26)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 50, Folder 27)
- Additional material, 1940-1944; Accession 2001-M-005
  The addition includes correspondence, photographs, and writings. The correspondence consists primarily of photocopies of letters to and from Warren Weinberger, Harry's nephew, regarding Warren's attempts to begin practicing law. The three photographs are printed copies of digital reproductions. Writings include photocopies of published addresses.
  - Correspondence
    - Lowe, Joe, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Weinberger, Warren, 1940-1944 (Box 1, Folder 2-5)
  - Photographs, Undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Printed copies of digital reproductions
  - Writings
    - "After the War, Jobs for All", 1943 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      Address in commemoration of the 104th birthday of Henry George
    - "Emma Goldman", 1940 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Speech delivered at her funeral
    - "My Philosophy", Undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Additional material, 1916-1931; Accession 2001-M-137
  The accession is arranged by type of material, including clippings, short stories, plays, and other writings by Harry Weinberger.
  - Clippings, 1916, 1926, 1931, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Letter from Gilbert Seldes, managing editor of The Dial
  - Plays
    - Blackmail, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Fear, Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Narcisse, Undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Where's Business?, Undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Poetry ["An Unemployed"], Undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Stories
    - "The Boy Who Had To Go To School", Undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - "Cash", Undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - "Collecting the Impossible", Undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - "Jettisoned", Undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - "Judged As One", 1922 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - "Proposals", Undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - "Raffles in Real Life", Undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - "The Step Upwards in Success", Undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - "Success or Suicide", Undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - "The Ugly Duckling", 1922 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Unidentified fragments, Undated (Box 1, Folder 18)